[
  {
    "questionText": "How do you declare an array of integers?",
    "options": ["int[] arr;", "array int arr;", "int arr[];", "Both a and c"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What does \"public\" mean in Java?",
    "options": ["Bathroom", "Constructor", "Access modifier", "Function"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is the default value of a local variable in Java?",
      "options": ["Undefined", "0", "false", "null"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What does HTML stand for?",
    "options": ["Home Tool Markup Language", "Hyperlinks Text Markup Language", "Hyper Text Markup Language", "Hyper Tool Markup Language"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which keyword is used to define a class in Java?",
    "options": ["define", "class", "object", "static"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is Json used for?",
    "options": ["Structure", "Vacuuming", "Data storage and transformation", "Animation"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following is not a primitive type in Java?",
    "options": ["int", "String", "double", "char"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "questionText": "How many times will this be executed?\n for (int i = 0; i < 5; i++)?",
    "options": ["0", "6", "Infinite", "5"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is the primary purpose of threads in a program?",
    "options": ["To make the program compile faster", "To reduce memory usage", "To execute multiple tasks at once", "To improve exception handling"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is the role of FXML in JavaFX?",
    "options": ["To define the UI layout and design", "To handle backend logic", "To manage event listeners", "To load images into the application"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which is the correct syntax to output\"Hello World\" in Java?",
    "options": ["echo(\"Hello World\");", "Console.WriteLine(\"Hello World\");", "System.out.println(\"Hello World\");", "print(\"Hello World\")"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which Java feature allows a method to have multiple implementations in different classes?",
    "options": ["Encapsulation", "Inheritance", "Abstraction", "Polymorphism"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which of these is not a valid access modifier in Java?",
    "options": ["public", "protected", "global", "private"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "questionText": "How do you create a variable with the numeric value 5??",
    "options": ["num x = 5;", "x = 5;", "int x = 5;", "float x = 5;"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is the output of System.out.println(10 + \"20\");?",
    "options": ["30", "1020", "Compilation error", "Runtime error"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which statement is used to stop a loop??",
    "options": ["break", "return", "abort", "exit"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is the purpose of the toString() method?",
    "options": ["Converts an object to a String", "Returns an objects memory address", "Compares two strings", "Converts a string to uppercase"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which operator can be used to compare two values?",
    "options": ["><", "=", "<>", "=="],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which method is used to sort a list in Java?",
    "options": ["Collections.sort()", "Arrays.sort()", "Both A and B", "sort()"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which of these is not a type of loop in Java?",
    "options": ["for", "while", "do-while", "foreach"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which keyword is used to inherit a class in Java?",
    "options": ["extends", "inherit", "extend", "super"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which method is used to compare two String objects for equality in Java?",
    "options": ["==", "isEqual()", "equals()", "compareTo()"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is the result of 10 / 3 in Java if both operands are integers?",
    "options": ["3.3333", "4", "Compilation error", "3"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is the purpose of the this. keyword in Java?",
    "options": ["Refers to the superclass", "Refers to the current object instance", "Refers to the current method", "Refers to a static variable"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which Java package contains the Scanner class?",
    "options": ["java.io", "java.lang", "java.util", "java.text"],
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2
  }
]
